I've still got a lot of years ahead of me
この想いを　消してしまうには
Kono omoi wo keshiteshimau niwa
To just erase these feelings?
まだ人生長いでしょ？
Mada jinsei nagai desho?
To just erase these feelings?
まだ人生長いでしょ？
I want to go back and finish
やり残してるコト
Yarinokoshiteru koto
The things that I've yet to finish.
やり直してみたいから
Yarinaoshite mitai kara
I was supposed to be chasing after my ongoing dream,
夢のつづき　追いかけていたはずなのに
Yume no tsuzuki oikaketeita hazu nanoni
Yet I faltered over others while walking this thin, winding path.
曲がりくねった　細い道　人につまずく
Magarikunetta hosoi michi hito ni tsumazuku
It's not that I want to return to those days.
あの頃みたいにって　戻りたい訳じゃないの
Ano koro mitainitte modoritai wake ja nai no
I'm searching for the sky I lost.
無くしてきた空を　探してる
Nakushitekita sora wo sagashiteru
Don't make that sad face, as if you've fallen victim.
わかってくれますように
Wakatte kuremasu youni
As if you want people to pity you.
犠牲になったような　悲しい顔はやめてよ
Gisei ni natta youna kanashii kao wa yameteyo
Tears aren't the end of your sins.
罪の最後は涙じゃないよ
Tsumi no saigo wa namida ja nai yo
You have to bear them painfully, forever.
ずっと苦しく背負ってくんだ
Zutto kurushiku seottekunda
Who are you waiting for in the maze of emotions,
出口見えない感情迷路に
Deguchi mienai kanjoumeiro ni
Where you can't even see the exit?
誰を待ってるの？
Dare wo matteruno?
I want to blurt it out more justly,
白いノートに綴ったように
Shiroi nooto ni tsuzutta youni
Just like how I wrote it in my white notebook.
もっと素直に吐き出したいよ
Motto sunao ni hakidashitai yo
What do you want to run from?
何から　逃れたいんだ
Nani kara nogaretainda
That thing called "reality"?
…現実ってやつ？
Genjitsu tte yatsu?
I just want to scream out,
叶えるために　生きてるんだって
Kanaeru tame ni ikiterundatte
"I'm only living to fulfill my wish." Can you hear me?
叫びたくなるよ　聞こえていますか？
Sakebitaku naru yo kikoeteimasuka?
I can't take the safe way out of everything.
無難になんて　やってられないから
Bunan ni nante yatterarenaikara
I don't even have a place to return to.
…帰る場所も無いの
Kaeru basho mo nai no
I'm always thankful for everyone's kindness,
優しさには　いつも感謝してる
Yasashisa ni wa itsumo kansha shiteru
That's why I want to become stronger. (I'm on the way)
だから強くなりたい(I'm on the the
(I'm on the way)
Dakara tsuyoku naritai (I'm on the way)
This is reminding me of the old days.
懐かしくなる
Natsukashiku naru
This pain is all right with me.
こんな痛みも歓迎じゃん
Konna itami mo kangei jan
あれがロイ·マスタングか
So that's Roy Mustang.
The Flame Alchemist, eh?
焔の錬金術師ねぇ
あの若さで抜擢とは
An exceptional promotion at that age?
I wonder what kind of connections he used.
どんなコネを使ったのか
They say the faster you rise, the faster you fall.
上がる速度が早いと　落ちる速度も早いものさ
Come in.
どうぞ
Sorry to bother you.
失礼します
I am Colonel Roy Mustang.
ロイ·マスタング大佐です
Ah, Colonel Mustang.
ああ　マスタング大佐
I apologize. The Führer President is out right now.
申し訳ありません
大総統閣下は　お出かけになられまして
To where?
どちらへ
He went to the South for an inspection.
南部へ視察に行かれました
South?
南部へ
I don't like this smell.
イヤなにおいがするぜ
But it smells familiar.
だが懐かしい　これは
This is...
I simply came for an inspection,
but it seems I just discovered something.
視察に来てみればとんだ見つけものだな
Move in!
突入
A brat and a housewife?! How grand.
小僧に主婦かこいつはいい
But I'm kind of ill-matched for a fight.
だが戦うにはちと相性が悪ぃな
I'll be making my escape.
逃げさせてもらう
You-
貴様
M-Master, hang in there!
せっ師匠　しっかり
Running away?! How cowardly...
逃げるとは　卑怯な
Master...
師匠
Master! Master!!!
師匠師匠
おとなしく　しなさい
Stay...
...still...
N...o...
イヤだ
Greed!
グリードさん
Looks like you're okay, Martel.
マーテル　お前は無事だったか
What happened? I haven't seen Roa and the others, either...
どうしたんですか　ロアたちも戻って来ないし
Yeah, things have become a little complicated.
ちょいと面倒なことになった
逃げる算段しないとな
We have to get out of here somehow.
I can't let you do that.
それは困る
Huh? Who are you, old man?
誰だ　おっさん
Führer President!
大総統　なんでここに
Why are you here?
King Bradley?!
キング·ブラッドレイ
へえ　この国で一番のお偉いさんがなんの用だよ
So what business does the most powerful guy in the country have with us?
How old are you?
君　年はいくつだね
Huh?
I'm turning sixty this year.
私は今年６０になる
When you get old, your body starts to not move the way you want it to.
年を取ると　体が思うように動かなくなってな
So I really want to get this over with and go home.
こんな仕事　さっさと終わらせて帰りたいのだよ
Retire already, gramps.
引退しな　おっさん
Whoa, whoa, whoa, you're not just an ordinary geezer, are you?!
おいおいおい　なんつうおっさんだ
Greed?!
グリードさん
Now you've seen it.
見たか
A skill that has been passed down in the Armstrong household for generations... Sculpture Alchemy!!!
これぞ我がアームストロング家に代々伝わりし彫像術
In that case, I won't hold back.
では本気でやらせてもらう
How strange...
なんと面妖な
We've ensured the safety of the boy and the housewife.
少年とご夫人は確保した
We'll proceed with the extermination of all the monsters!
あとは化け物どもを殲滅する
大総統のご命令だ
It's an order from the Führer President!
It's been a while since anyone's gotten me so excited.
久しぶりに血湧き肉躍る
Nothing less to be expected from Sir Armstrong.
さすがアームストロング殿
I also participated in the Ishbal extermination.
オレもイシュヴァール殲滅戦に参加していた
Former ally, eh?
元同志か
Then all the more reason not to kill you.
ならばなおさら　無駄な殺生は好まぬ
Surrender at once.
投降せよ
Even though you're planning on killing me?
殺すつもりなのにか
Major!
少佐
ロア
Roa!
Bastard!!!
野郎っ
You see,
私はね　君のような最強の盾を持っているわけでも
I don't have an ultimate shield like you,
nor an ultimate spear that pierces diamond.
すべてを貫く最強の矛を持っているわけでもない
Do you understand how someone like that could have survived countless battles,
そんな私が　どうやって弾丸飛び交う戦場を生き抜き
rendered distinguished service,
and has achieved the rank I have right now?
功績を立てて今の地位にいるか
分かるかね
Y...ou...
お前
君に最強の盾があるように
Just as you have an ultimate shield,
I have an ultimate eye.
私には最強の目があるのだよ
Now, Greed.
さて　グリード君
How many times do I have to kill you to get rid of you for good?
君はあと何回殺せば死ぬのかねぇ
Where's Greed?
グリードさんは
I don't know.
分からない　暗くてよく見えない
It's too dark; I can't see anything.
グリードさん
Greed?!
ダメだ
No!
Hey! Open up!
この　開けなさいよ
No!
ダメ
Let me out!
出しなさい
I said no!
ダメったらダメ
That was fifteen deaths, wasn't it?
これで１５回は死んだか
How many more do you have? Hmm?
あと何回かね　うん
Y-You bastard...
て　てめぇ
Dammit...
くそ　大総統じきじきかよ
The Führer President himself is here?
I don't mind if you run off with your tail between your legs.
しっぽを巻いて逃げてもいいぞ
I'd love to,
そうしたいところだが
犬ってのは忠誠心が強くてよ
but dogs are loyal animals.
Please, get her out of here.
そいつを逃がしてやってくれ
We're counting on you.
頼んだぞ
Roa?! Dolcetto?!
ロア　ドルチェット
Hey, quit interfering! Let me out!
ちょっと　邪魔しないで
出しなさい
I won't!
イヤだ
I don't have time to mess with you!
あんたとここでやり合ってる暇はないのよ
I'm telling you to open up!
開けろって言ってんの
ダメだよ　出ちゃダメだ
No! You can't come out!
Shut up and open up!
いいから　開けなさい
Are you telling me to just sit and watch my friends be killed?!
仲間が殺られるのをここで黙って見てろっての
I can't let you out!
出すわけにはいかない
They asked me to keep you safe!
頼まれたんだ　二人に
ドルチェット
Dolcetto!!!
Roa!!!
ロア
お願いだから
Please, I'm begging you...
You can't... come out.
出ちゃ　ダメだ
Hey, hey, Mister Bradley.
おいおい　ブラッドレイさんよ
You really think you'll get away with doing this to my men?
オレの部下をこんなにしちまって
駒に情が移ったか
You're feeling sympathetic now? How silly.
くだらん
Sympathy?
情だぁ
Are you stupid?
アホか　オレを誰だと思ってんだ
Who do you think I am?
I'm Greed.
強欲のグリード様だぞ
Money, women, subordinates...
金も　女も　部下も
...everything belongs to me!
何もかもオレの所有物なんだよ
Which is why I won't abandon what's mine.
だから　オレはオレの所有物を見捨てねぇ
I'm a greedy guy, after all!!!
何せ欲が深いからなぁ
Greedy? This is beyond silly.
強欲　ますますくだらん
How about you lie there for a while.
しばらく寝ているがよい
I have to get out of here...
逃げなきゃ
Hang on.
待ちたまえ
You're Edward's brother, aren't you?
エドワード君の弟だね
Are you hurt? Let me lend you a hand.
ケガはないか　手を貸そう
N-No, I'm fine.
あっはい　いえ大丈夫です
I can go back by myself.
一人で帰れますから
No, Martel!
ダメだ　マーテルさん
ブラッドレイ
Bradley!!!
アル
Al!!!
か　母さん
M-Mom!
母さん
Mom! Mom!!!
アル　おいしっかりしろ
Al! Hang in there!
おい　返事しろよ
Hey, say something!
アル
Al!
兄さん
Brother...
大丈夫か
You all right?
兄さんこそ　そんな血まみれで
You're covered in blood, too, Brother...
勝手に開いて　引っ張り出させてもらった
I opened you up and pulled her body out.
助けられなかった
I couldn't save her...
アルは悪くないよ
It's not your fault.
さあ　帰ろう
Come on. Let's go back.
アル
Al...
待ちたまえ
Hold there.
君たちには聞かねばならんことがある
I've got something I need to ask you both.
ここの黒幕　グリードという男とは
The mastermind of this incident, Greed. Is he an acquaintance of yours?
知り合いかね
いいえ
No, sir.
重要な情報を聞き出したりは
Did you happen to obtain
any important information from him?
何も　軍の利益になるようなことは
Nothing that would benefit the army, no.
Don't misunderstand me. Not for the army.
勘違いするな　軍のためではない
もしヤツらと取り引きしていたら
If you were making a deal with them...
場合によっては
...depending on your answer...
軍の中枢に害なすヤツらと手を結んだのか
Did you ally yourself with people whose intent was to harm the mainstay of the army?
No, sir.
いいえ　ほかに質問は
Any other questions?
君の鋼の腕と弟の鎧姿
Your steel arm and your brother's body.
何か関係があるのかね
They're related, are they not?
正直者だな
You're an honest one.
引き揚げるぞ
Time to withdraw.
君のその弟　大切にしたまえよ
Take good care of your little brother, you hear?
エルリック兄弟のこと　ありがとうございました
I deeply appreciate you saving those two boys.
なんの　国家錬金術師の身を守るのも軍の任務の一つ
Don't worry about it.
It's one of the duties of the army to protect State Alchemists, too.
どうですかな　あなたも軍に守られてみては
How about it?
Would you like to be protected by the army, too?
国家錬金術師に
Become a State Alchemist?
Precisely.
いかにも
見てのとおり　私は病弱な主婦です
As you can see, I'm a frail housewife.
そんな者の力を借りねばならぬほど
Is this country so strained as to require the help of someone like me?
この国は逼迫しているのですか
手厳しいですな
Harsh words!
また　来ますよ
I'll come again.
その時には　心変わりしているかもしれませんからな
You may have changed your mind by then.
グリードってヤツ
That Greed guy had a tattoo of Ouroboros on his hand.
手にウロボロスの入れ墨があったんだ
ウロボロス
Ouroboros...
ほら　ヒューズ中佐にも話しただろ
You heard me telling Lt. Colonel Hughes, didn't you?
賢者の石にかかわってるヤツらだよ
They're people who have something to do with the philosopher's stones.
ヒューズ殿
Sir Hughes...
エドワ－ド·エルリック
Edward Elric.
あまり　ムチャをするなよ
Don't do anything too reckless, all right?
ああ
Okay...
では　な
Well then...
兄さん
Brother.
あのさ
My memories of when my body was taken have returned.
僕の体があっちに持ってかれたときの記憶が戻ったんだ
どうだった
How was it?!
Well...
なんかすごかった
It was kind of extraordinary...
でも人体錬成については分からなかった
But I couldn't find anything about human transmutation.
そっか
I see...
結局進歩なしか
In the end, no progress, eh...
いや　そうでもないさ
Not necessarily.
Remember what the Führer President said?
大総統前に言ってたろ
軍内部に不穏な動きがあるって
That there have been disquieting activities within the military.
Yeah, he said that it had something to do with philosopher's stones and the people who have tattoos of Ouroboros...
賢者の石や
ウロボロスの入れ墨を持つヤツらにかかわってるって
He said he wanted to catch them for that reason, right?
だからしっぽをつかみたいって言ってたね
グリードもウロボロスの入れ墨を持ってた
Greed also had that tattoo.
なら　なんで皆殺しにする必要がある
If so, why did he need to kill them all?
しっぽをつかみたいなら
If he really wanted to know what they were up to,
he should have captured and interrogated them, right?
とっつかまえて聞き出しゃいいだろ
You're right.
そうだよね
And besides, it's strange the Führer President himself came to the battlefield when there weren't that many enemies.
それにたったあれだけの人数をやっつけるのに
大総統が出てくるってのもおかしいよ
ああ　どうにも納得できないことばかりだ
Yeah. Everything just seems so fishy.
しばらく　軍にくっついてみるか
Guess we'll stick with the army for a little longer.
お帰りなさい　大総統
Welcome back, Führer President.
南部の視察はどうだった
How did the inspection of the South go?
鋼の錬金術師の弟
The Fullmetal Alchemist's brother...
ひょっとしたら
...and perhaps their master, too.
二人の師匠も人柱になりうる人材かもしれん
Both of them may also be suitable sacrifices.
そしてもう一つ　思わぬ収穫が
I also found something else that was unexpected.
あら　懐かしいわね
Oh my, now that's someone I haven't seen in a while.
１世紀前にここを出た顔だわ
He left this place a century ago.
起きなさい　グリード
Wake up, Greed.
おやまぁ　皆さんおそろいで
Oh wow, looks like everyone's here.
いいざまね　最強の盾
So much for your ultimate shield.
You look as gorgeous as you did a century ago.
おめぇは相変わらずいい女だな
最強の矛　色欲のラストさんよ
Miss Lust, the "Ultimate Spear".
And Gluttony, you haven't lost weight at all.
暴食のグラトニー
おめぇはちっともやせねぇな
嫉妬のエンヴィー
And, Envy? You still dress like that?
またそんな趣味の悪ぃ格好してんのか
怠惰のスロウスはどこだ
Where's Sloth at?
昔からサボってばかりでね
He always skips out on meetings.
まだ仕事中よ
He's working right now.
ほんとにどいつもこいつも
Seriously, none of you guys have changed over a hundred years.
１００年前から変わっちゃいねぇな
And who's this guy?
で
こいつは誰だ
I am Wrath.
憤怒のラース
Wrath?
ラースだぁ　キング·ブラッドレイだろ
Aren't you King Bradley?
そう
Yup. He's our last sibling Father created as a human by the name of King Bradley.
キング·ブラッドレイという名の人間として
お父様が最後の詰めに用意された
私たちの兄弟
年を取る人造人間　そんなんありか
An aging Homunculus?!
Is that even possible?
「ありえないなんてことはありえない」
"There's no way there's no way."
あんたの口癖だったはずだよ
I thought that was a stock phrase of yours. Don't tell me you forgot?
忘れたの
Or are you going senile?
それとももうろく
黙ってろやブサイクが
Shut your mouth, you ugly shit.
What was that?
Hey, I like those eyes. That's the way you ought to be.
いいね　その目そうでなくっちゃ
How about you show your true colors every once in a while, Envy the Bizarre.
久しぶりに本性見せろよ
ゲテモノエンヴィー
You piece of shit...
クソが
望みどおり踏み潰してやるよ
I'll kick your ass, if that's what you're asking for.
よさないか　お前たち
Cut it out, all of you.
兄弟で争うなど
Please don't fight among siblings, especially in front of your father.
そんな醜いことはこの父の前でしてくれるな
Yo, old man.
よう　おやじ殿
しばらく見ないうちに随分老け込んだんじゃねぇの
Looks like you've aged a lot since the last time I saw you.
グリード　我が魂を分けた息子よ
Greed.
You are my son who shares my soul.
なぜこの父を裏切った
Why did you betray me?
"Why"?
なぜだと
それはおやじ殿がいちばん分かってることじゃないのか
Shouldn't you know best?
I am Greed.
強欲のグリード
あんたがそう産んで　オレはそのとおり生きただけだ
That's how you gave me life, and that's the way I've lived.
あんたのもとにいたんじゃ
If I stayed by your side, I wouldn't be able to obtain everything my greedy soul desires.
このオレの欲は満たされねぇんだよ
また私のために働いてくれんか
Will you work for me again?
ノーだ
No can do!
そうか
I see...
I really don't like your tastes...
ほんと　趣味悪ぃ
This is how hot I like my baths, damnit!
いい湯加減だな　ちくしょ
地獄の業火は　これほどぬるくはねぇだろうよ
I'm sure the flames of Hell are hotter than this!
どんなもんか　先に行って見ててやるぜ　兄弟
I'll go on ahead to see what it's like, my siblings!
生まれた場所へ　我が魂へ還るがよい
Go back to where you came from, my soul, Greed!
グリードよ
You don't even have to ask!!!
上等だ
Don't blame me if you get a stomachache, old man!!!
腹壊しても知らねぇぞ　おやじ殿
来るべき日に向けて
To the forthcoming day,
お前たちの変わらぬ忠誠と安寧を祈る
I pray for the unchanging loyalty of you all, along with peace and order.
お父さん
Dad!
おかえりなさい　お父さん
Welcome back, Dad!
ただいま　セリム
Thank you, Selim.
視察はどうでした
How was the inspection?
実に充実した視察だったぞ
It was a substantial inspection all right.
あなた　もう若くないのですから
Dear, you're getting older...
後進に席を譲って
Why not give up your position to a junior and relax?
ゆっくりなさったらいいのに
いやいや　まだ現役だぞ
No, no, I'm still in my prime.
おおそうだ　南で鋼の錬金術師に会ったぞ
Oh, that's right. I met the
Fullmetal Alchemist while in the South.
The short alchemist? Really?!
小さい錬金術師の　本当ですか
セリムはエドワードさんの話が好きね
You really love hearing about Mr. Edward, don't you, Selim?
だって　最年少の国家錬金術師なんて
He's the youngest State Alchemist! That's just so cool!
かっこいいじゃないですか
That's awesome. I want to learn alchemy, too!
いいなぁ　僕も錬金術習いたい
What in the world would you do with it?
そんなもの習ってどうするの
国家資格を取って
I want to get a state qualification to be useful to Dad.
お父さんの役に立ちたいんです
では将来は　セリムに手伝ってもらうかな
Then I might ask for your help in the future.
Say, the sky we saw that day, the scarlet sky.
あの日見た空　茜色の空を
Ano hi mita sora akaneiro no sora wo
Do you remember it from that day?
ねえ　君は覚えていますか
Nee kimi wa oboeteimasuka
We made a promise and a vow while the early summer wind circled us.
約束　契り　初夏の風が包む
Yakusoku chigiri shoka no kaze ga tsutsumu
And we clung close together.
二人　寄り添った
Futari yorisotta
Your forced smile
無理な笑顔の裏
Muri na egao no ura
Holds elongated shadows.
伸びた影をかくまう
Nobita kage wo kakumau
I pretend not to notice and continue on.
だから　気づかぬふり　再生を選ぶ
Dakara kizukanu furi saisei wo erabu
All the while waiting for you to deliver some news at the table.
テーブルの上の　震えない知らせ　待ち続けて
Teeburu no ue no furuenai shirase machitsuzukete
Empty nights, mornings that will never arrive,
空白の夜も　来るはずのない朝も
Kuuhaku no yoru mo kuru hazu no nai asa mo
I could see them from a mile away.
全部わかってたんだ
Zenbu wakattetanda
Say, the sky we saw that day, the scarlet sky.
あの日見た空　茜色の空を
Ano hi mita sora akaneiro no sora wo
I'm sure you'll remember it one day.
ねえ　 いつか思い出すでしょう
Nee itsuka omoidasu deshou
While holding the promise we couldn't keep,
果たせなかった　約束を抱いて
Hatasenakatta yakusoku wo idaite
We take our first steps down our own paths.
二人　歩き出す
Futari arukidasu
日本語字幕仕上げ：FAYFAY
異邦人の投げ込む小石は
The pebbles foreigners throw into the water create ripples, and as they link together, they create a huge whirlpool.
波紋となって連鎖し合い
漫遊字幕組
http://popgo.net/bbs
やがて　大きな渦を作る
見よ　今まさにその瞬間
Look! That's precisely what's happening right now.
次回　鋼の錬金術師
Next time, Fullmetal Alchemist:
FULLMETAL ALCHEMIST
第十五話　東方の使者
Episode 15, Envoy From the East.
我　笑みの内に刃を持ちて
I hide my blade behind my smile
and seek the Philosopher's Stone.
賢者の石に辿り着かん